http://www.ipcc.ie/about-us/privacy-policy/

Irish Peatland Conservation Council
Action for Bogs and Wildlife in Ireland
Skip to content
HomeAbout UsLocationOpening TimesHistory of the IPCCContact UsDonate To IPCCData Protection StatementDonor CharterPrivacy PolicyJob OpportunitiesIPCC’s Five Year PlanIPCC’s Mission and WorkIPCC’s Success StoriesIPCC’s Annual Report & Financial Statements 2019AdviceComposting DIYComposting Using A Heap, Cone or BinComposting Using A WormeryComposted Leaves – Leaf MouldWildlife Gardening TipsPeatland Management DIY Tool KitPeatland Restoration MonitoringRestoration of Burned PeatlandsRestoration of Drained PeatlandsRestoration of Forested PeatlandsRestoration of Overgrazed PeatlandsRestoration of Industrial Cutaway PeatlandsPeatland Management FAQ’s & Project LinksRestoration of Sphagnum Moss Growth on PeatlandsContact UsDiscover & LearnIPCC’s Peatland Nature ReservesIPCC’s conservation and education programme for Curlew on Lodge Bog€40,500 for IPCC Bog NetworkCoad Bog, Co. Kerry Visitor Map and GuideFenor Bog, Waterford, Visitor Map & GuideGirley Bog, Co. Meath Visitor Map & GuideGirley Bog Wildlife Gallery by Natasha SullivanLodge Bog, Co. Kildare Visitor Map & GuideLullymore West Bog, Co. Kildare Visitor Map & GuideGo Wild Nature CampsResourcesBog Plant BookBogland Food WebBog Watch Flower Identification DialBog Watch Pool Bug Identification DialHow to Make a St Bridget’s CrossBog in a Bottle – Blanket Bog FormationBog Field Studies ProgrammesBog in a Bottle – Raised Bog FormationBog Walk Scavenger HuntSchool VisitsHeritage in Schools VisitsDiscover Primary Science & MathsBioBog – Raising Awareness of Biodiversity in the Bog of AllenSEAI WorkshopsTraining CoursesFlytrappers – Carnivorous PlantsHelp IPCCOffset Your Carbon FootprintHop To It National Frog Survey Ireland CardJoin IPCC’s Anti-Moss Peat CampaignLeave A LegacyVolunteer with IPCCBe a Peat-Free GardenerButterfly Project – Lullymore West BogStamp CollectingGirley Bog RestorationGirley Bog Top 10Gift CatalogueJoin IPCCPurchase an Acre of Endangered BoglandA to Z
Booklet of Fundraising IdeasShopNature ShopVisitor AttractionBog of Allen Nature Centre Visitor Guide & MapPrimary School VisitsSecondary School VisitsFamily VisitsGroup VisitsIndividual VisitsInternational Bog DayPeatland Passport IrelandThe Gathering Ireland 2013 – Bog MemoriesPeat Crossing BorderlinesPhotogallery of Peat Crossing Borderlines 2018A to Z PeatlandsIPCC Policy and Case WorkAction for CurlewAtlas of the Natural and Cultural Heritage of LullymoreBlanket BogsBog WoodlandsCarnivorous Plants – Killers in the BogDutch-Irish Bog ConservationFensFrogsMarsh Fritillary ButterflyPeatland Action PlanExtent & Utilisation of Irish PeatlandsDesignation of Peatlands of Conservation ImportancePeatland Site List of Conservation Importance in IrelandHalting the Loss of Peatland BiodiversityHabitat Loss of PeatlandsClimate Change and Irish PeatlandsOver-Exploitation of Peatlands for PeatInvasive Species on Irish PeatlandsNutrient Pollution of PeatlandsPeatlands – A Future in Ireland?Raised BogsSphagnum Moss – the Bog BuilderDonate
Privacy Policy
The Irish Peatland Conservation Council (IPCC) is committed to protecting your privacy and security. Whenever you provide personal information, we will treat that information in accordance with this policy, current Irish Data Protection legislation and Internet best practice. You can use most of the features of the IPCC web site site without disclosing any personal information. A few optional features of this site, such as friend of the bog enrolment forms, frog survey forms or on line shop purchases, ask you to provide some personal information (eg. name and address, e-mail address). This Statement of Privacy applies to the IPCC Web site (www.ipcc.ie) and governs data collection and usage. By using the IPCC website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement. Please take the time to read our Privacy Policy below.
Collection of your Personal Information
IPCC collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. IPCC also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.
There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by IPCC. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by IPCC for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the IPCC Web site.
Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through IPCC public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: IPCC does not read any of your private online communications.
IPCC encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from IPCC so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. IPCC is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the IPCC and IPCC family of Web sites.
Use of your Personal Information
IPCC collects and uses your personal information to operate the IPCC Web site and deliver the services you have requested. IPCC also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from IPCC and its affiliates. IPCC may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.
IPCC does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. IPCC may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, IPCC may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to IPCC, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.
IPCC does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.
IPCC keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within IPCC, in order to determine what IPCC services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within IPCC to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.
IPCC Web sites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on IPCC or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of IPCC; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of IPCC, or the public.
Use of Cookies
The IPCC Web site uses “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.
One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize IPCC pages, or register with IPCC site or services, a cookie helps IPCC to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same IPCC Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the IPCC features that you customized.
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the IPCC services or Web sites you visit.
Security of your Personal Information
IPCC secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. IPCC secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.
Changes to this Statement
IPCC will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. IPCC encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how IPCC is protecting your information.
Contact Information
IPCC welcomes your comments and questions regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that IPCC has not adhered to this Statement, please contact us at bogs@ipcc.ie or IPCC, Lullymore, Rathangan, Co. Kildare. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
Categories
Downloads
Events
News
Uncategorized
Visitor Attraction – Bog of Allen Nature Centre
Wildlife Watch at the Bog of Allen Nature Centre
Bog Blog
While The Horticultural Industry Talks about Change, Habitat and Wildlife Destruction Continues
Celebrating Heritage Week 2020 with the Irish Peatland Conservation Council – Virtually!
IPCC Welcome the Imminent Publication of the 100th Irish Wildlife Manual
A Call to Action this International Bog Day
Shocking degradation of Irish Peatlands needs Action Plan with Climate focus
Proudly powered by WordPress.
